What's wrong?
Are you okay?
I think I sprained my ankle.
Hop on. I'll carry you.
Take her weapon.
Help her up.
Let's go.
You seem to be in a good mood.
You even have time to design a report cover.
Actually, this operation
isn't that difficult from a technical standpoint.
The real challenge is gathering intelligence
and pulling off an effective deception.
Yeah.
Right now, everything is ready.
We're just waiting on the final piece.
Don't worry.
Squad Leader Hong can complete this operation.
Stay alert
Binoculars.
Yes, sir.
Found it.
How come I didn't see it?
All their light sources are completely covered up.
They're completely invisible to the naked eye.
But
night vision binoculars are very sensitive to light spots.
Use the night vision equipment right now
to lock in their coordinates
and capture their frequency bands.
Yes, sir.
Platoon Leader Yang, you're awesome!
I wonder what Guo Zijian
is really up to.
He's always pulling these mysterious tricks.
Since the sea training, this is
the Yufeng Battalion
and the 404th Brigade's
first direct confrontation.
It's also Guo Zijian
and Long Yuanshan's
first truly meaningful
showdown.
So,
acting cautiously to avoid leaking intel
is perfectly normal.
Wangyuan,
I think
your attitude toward Guo Zijian
from now on
should be more objective.
Don't always be so prejudiced.
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo,
after this sea training,
I feel like you've changed.
In what way?
Your attitude toward us old subordinates has changed.
You and Jiang Shengqiang are soldiers I trained myself.
I know you very well,
like you're my own children.
In the past,
I was a bit lenient.
My own standards
weren't very high, either.
But in the long run,
that might have harmed you.
Wangyuan,
I hope
you'll all focus your energy on work from now on.
What's going on with you today?
Did Guo Zijian brainwash you again?
Let's wait until the exercise is over.
We'll find some time
to have a good talk.
Hong Xiafei sent a message.
Confirmed the Blue Army command post is in Wolf Valley.
Good.
Attention, entire Yufeng Battalion.
Officially initiate
Operation Diana.
Yes, sir.
Report.
The Red Army command post has been spotted.
Is the location confirmed?
Not confirmed yet,
but we can determine
that its position has changed.
If he wants a fight to the death with me,
he needs to have what it takes.
Connect to all battalions immediately.
Yes, sir.
Report. Connection successful.
Attention, all battalions.
This is Long Yuanshan.
The Red Army reserves,
after merging with their remaining forces,
are very likely to mount a desperate last stand
to try and turn the tide of defeat.
I order:
One.
Stay on high alert and avoid sneak attacks.
Two.
Once the Brigade Command confirms the enemy target,
all battalions must cooperate fully
to finish them off in a single strike.
Three.
According to recon analysis,
the Red Army reserves are only one combined arms battalion strong,
and they have already been deployed separately.
Once any battalion spots the target,
you may execute a strike independently.
Over.
1st Battalion, copy.
2nd Battalion, copy.
3rd Battalion, copy.
Don't rush.
The best part is yet to come.
Platoon Leader,
we spotted a Blue Army recon squad ahead.
They're heading this way.
Has anyone used the radio communication system?
No.
Good. We haven't been compromised.
Lin Yihu.
Here!
Lead Squad One and protect Squad Leader Hong.
Unless absolutely necessary,
do not expose your position.
Yes, sir.
Platoon Leader, what about you?
I have to get captured.
It's the only way to dispel the Blue Force's suspicions.
Let me go instead.
They won't believe it if you go.
Squad Two, follow me.
Operation Great Shift is ready.
1st Battalion.
1st Battalion, standing by.
Orders.
The Red Army's main reserve force
is confirmed at grid square 3850.
For operations in this area,
your battalion is best positioned.
Quickly deploy heavy firepower
for saturation fire
to annihilate the enemy.
1st Battalion, copy.
2nd Battalion.
2nd Battalion, standing by.
Confirmed:
the Red Army's main reserve force
is at grid square 3857.
Your battalion is best positioned for this area.
Quickly deploy heavy firepower
for saturation fire to annihilate the enemy.
2nd Battalion, copy.
3rd Battalion.
3rd Battalion, standing by.
Orders.
Director Zhou,
what's the situation?
The battle has started.
Long Yuanshan was just issuing strike orders.
And the coordinates were highly precise.
Any activity from the Red Army?
We've been monitoring them.
They emitted a brief signal just now,
but have now resumed radio silence.
Professor Zhang,
you went to the restroom
and missed a great show.
Is that so?
Grenade
Let's go, Platoon Leader Yang.
This trick
is pretty underhanded.
In the eyes of the Blue Army's long-range artillery,
the 399th Brigade's command post
instantly became
Long Yuanshan's command post.
Didn't he want to find the Red Army's brain?
I marked it for him.
You are
using Long Yuanshan's own long-range artillery
to strike his own command post?
Isn't that a bit too ruthless?
When Long Yuanshan figures it out,
won't he go crazy?
Think about it,
when has he ever been soft on us?
This is Goddess Diana's revenge.
Those who desecrate her will eventually become prey,
killed by their own hunting companions.
This is Project Diana.
Then what should our team
be doing right now?
Clean up the battlefield
and reap the fruits of victory.
Signalman!
Sir!
Get me Deputy Brigade Commander Suo.
Yes, sir!
Probably worried that making any sound
would easily expose them,
so during the capture,
everyone's individual communication system
was turned off.
I can confirm
that Yang Maolin
didn't transmit a single word out.
So you're saying this reserve force of the 399th Brigade
is your Yufeng Battalion.
Staff Officer Wang!
Sir!
Notify all battalions immediately:
Yufeng Battalion has entered the battle.
Be extremely careful of that little fox, Guo Zijian.
Yes, sir!
The little fox is still green.
He can't outsmart an old fox like you.
Haven't you heard the story
of wild punches beating an old master?
If we had known from the very beginning
that our opponent was Yufeng Battalion,
it wouldn't be scary.
But the fact that he still hasn't
shown his true colors until now
is truly a bit terrifying.
Being uninformed,
unaware,
and unprepared,
makes them the most dangerous rival.
Tell me,
how did you sneak in here, kid?
Chief,
what I know
is just as much as you do.
Scram, scram! Get him out of here!
Just seeing him annoys me.
Little brat!
Didn't even call during the holidays!
He did call me, actually.
He probably called me too.
I just missed it.
I agree with your suggestion.
Wolf Valley.
Isn't Wolf Valley Blue Army territory?
This Guo Zijian wants to use you as a human shield again!
He wants to give me an opportunity
to win back my pride.
Staff Officer Hu!
Sir!
Deploy a platoon from the reserve force.
Have them take two
combat helicopters
and escort Deputy Brigade Commander Suo
to collect Brigade Commander Long's body.
Ground forces are already approaching.
No need to worry about security.
Yes, sir!
Staff Officer Liang!
Sir!
Launch the final attack!
Yes, sir!
Blue Army Artillery Fire Support,
please respond if you copy.
Artillery Fire Support.
It's confirmed
that the Red Army command post
is in Wolf Valley.
Coordinates sent.
Please execute a precision strike immediately.
Ultra-long-range firepower copies.
Look, Old Liang,
is that it?
Are you really using the Yufeng Battalion?
I feel like if you pulled out any random battalion,
we'd at least hear some noise tonight.
No.
How would I dare disobey the commander's orders?
I issued all these missions personally.
Then that's really weird.
So this is what you two had in mind.
You wanted the Yufeng Battalion to show off.
The results are in.
Well?
The Yufeng Battalion is simply not ready.
They are far from capable of three-dimensional combat,
long-range mobility,
and platform operations.
Besides, they just
rushed back from hundreds of kilometers away.
Staff Officer Wang!
Here!
Notify everyone.
As originally planned,
in ten minutes,
we relocate the command post.
Yes, sir!
What's going on?
Look.
What is this?
Why the sudden twist?
No way.
This comeback by the Yufeng Battalion is too bizarre.
The 404th Brigade
used its own firepower
to strike its own command post?
How is that possible?
Could our exercise control system
have been taken over by them too?
Commander Long! Commander Long!
The exercise is over.
Please step out of your command post with dignity.
Commander Long! Commander Long!
The exercise is over.
Please step out of your command post with dignity.
As bizarre as it seems,
the facts cannot be changed.
In this battle,
they used information and firepower warfare,
and even strategic and espionage warfare.
Interesting.
Professor Zhang.
Staying up all night tonight
wasn't a waste of time, was it?
Indeed.
This battle
made me see Guo Zijian's Value Cube
in a completely new light.
The facts fully prove that you are right.
Future combat
is moving toward miniaturization,
modularity, and intelligence.
Multi-dimensional development
is unstoppable.
Lao Liang,
it's not that you moved too fast.
It's that I'm old
and too conservative.
Professor Zhang,
you're being too modest.
Besides Guo Zijian,
another contributor, a great one,
is also your top student.
Comrades of the Blue Force,
good work out there.
You fought well.
Good work to you, Brigade Commander Long.
The same battlefield,
a similar night sky,
only
the outcome is reversed.
Feels familiar, doesn't it?
If Deputy Commander Suo commanded personally
and captured a live Long Yuanshan,
the result would be even more perfect.
There's no need.
To kill a chicken,
you don't need a butcher's knife.
A battalion commander under me can handle it.
As long as I can personally
collect your corpse,
that's perfect enough.
History is written by the victors.
I have nothing to say.
Staff Officer Hu!
Sir!
Clear the battlefield.
Yes, sir!
All right,
let's wait for dawn.
See you in the control hall.
He only won this one time.
Look how smug he is.
"Wait for dawn"? Give me a break.
He's full of it.
All right.
Let's go.
Let's go and listen
to exactly where we lost this time.
Our idea
comes from an ancient Greek myth.
Legend has it that
Diana, goddess of the moon,
was bathing in the forest
when a hunter in the forest,
Actaeon, searching for deer,
accidentally saw her.
In order to take revenge on Actaeon,
Diana turned him into a deer,
causing his own teammates and hounds
to mistake him for prey and brutally kill him.
This time, the Black Mamba 404th Brigade
became the pitiful Actaeon.
The idea for the entire operational plan
came from our Battalion Commander Guo.
Of course,
his proposal of the idea
was mostly based on our whole team's
operational characteristics and strength.
Battalion Commander Guo has stated more than once
that the combination of the Value Cube
is always based on battlefield realities.
Therefore,
how the cube transforms,
whether the operational scale is large or small,
whether the firepower strike is light or heavy,
whether the personnel deployed are many or few,
whether weapons and equipment are increased or decreased,
are all based on
the operational target
and the actual battlefield conditions.
So then,
the tactic implemented by Guo Zijian and your team,
using the enemy's spear to attack their shield,
what is its primary basis?
Reporting to the commander,
the reason our idea could be realized
is mainly due to the following conditions.
One,
the opponent was unaware of Yufeng Battalion's involvement.
Two,
the opponent was extremely confident in their info strength.
Three,
regarding the location of their command post,
the opponent never had any doubts.
Four,
our information platforms were highly compatible.
Five,
our various operational modules
executed their deception functions flawlessly.
This also includes
a series of directional misdirections
by Zeng Muhan's team.
Six,
we knew the opponent's communication frequencies, bands,
and their switching characteristics
like the back of our hand.
Of course, there are other reasons as well,
but these six points
are the most crucial factors.
Could you explain this using a specific combat example?
Yes.
In this operation,
the sole mission of Yang Maolin's special ops platoon
was to ensure the information warfare team completed its mission.
You could say
the mission was set by the information warfare team,
but during the specific implementation process,
the special ops platoon provided reasonable suggestions multiple times,
and at the final critical moment,
Yang Maolin split his forces into two.
He took the initiative to expose himself,
and perished together with the Blue Force,
thereby ensuring
the successful strike on the Blue Force command structure.
Furthermore,
when Zeng Muhan's team encountered enemy reconnaissance en route,
they were able to skillfully neutralize it,
and deepened the Blue Force's
fixed impression of our striking force pattern,
providing an effective illusion for our information warfare.
What does this illustrate?
It shows that human subjective initiative,
whether yesterday, today,
or in the future,
always exceeds the weapons and equipment themselves
with even greater value potential.
I know
many people might think
that our Yufeng Battalion's exercise this time
was successful
because we had a certain
technological advantage.
True.
Operation Diana, which we executed today,
indeed benefited from
the right time, place, and people.
But our battalion commander always emphasizes
that combat itself is the interplay of the expected and unexpected.
When the battlefield situation allows for a tactical advantage,
failing to seize it means a missed opportunity.
When the situation is unfavorable to us,
forcing an attack means losing our position.
So,
although technologically
we did have some advantages,
without our battalion commander's
unique creativity,
along with his guidance to
adapt to specific changes on the battlefield,
our ideas
would only exist in theory,
and be far from translating into an actual victory.
Brigade Commander Long.
The "Sword and Rainbow" duo
certainly lives up to its reputation.
You two truly are the perfect golden duo.
I'm actually a little jealous.
If I had managed to get Guo Zijian
transferred to my unit back then,
would I have gotten a buy-one-get-one deal,
and scored Staff Officer Liang too?
Brigade Commander Long,
the soldiers were just joking around.
Why are you joining in on the teasing?
This guy is full of tricks.
You need to be careful.
The smarter the girl,
the easier she falls for guys like him.
Now you're just blatantly sowing discord.
Alright.
I admit defeat this time.
We'll have plenty of chances out on the field.
We'll battle again next time.
What kind of man is he talking about?
Probably someone like the instructor.
The slightly sleazy type.
You two little rascals.
Pulling a stunt like this today,
you even managed to fool me.
What's that saying on the internet?
When the times abandon you,
they won't even say goodbye.
When I was young, I loved taking photos.
I used film back then.
A few years later, digital cameras came out,
and film became obsolete.
After a few years with digital cameras,
smartphones could take pictures too.
You see?
While you're still searching for the enemy,
the battlefield is already gone.
During today's drill,
I felt exactly like that.
Sir, you're being modest.
That's why we
must continuously learn
to improve
and reinvent ourselves.
Otherwise,
we'll just be left behind by the times.
Yes, sir.
I personally
feel the exact same way.
You feel that way too?
Then I guess we're about even.
No, no, no, sir.
I wouldn't dare claim that.
The battle lasted all night.
And the meeting lasted all day.
You all rest up here.
We'll head back tomorrow.
Since you won the battle,
I'm granting you
an extra day off.
There'll be a celebratory dinner tonight.
Let's celebrate properly.
There won't be any Level 3 combat readiness alerts, right?
You just reminded me.
Let me tell you,
anything is possible.
No, there won't be. Tonight,
just have a good time.
Yes, Sir!
Lao Suo.
You don't mind me calling you Lao Suo, do you?
Not at all.
What I want to say is,
for Yufeng Battalion
and Guo Zijian to be where they are today,
you deserve a lot of the credit.
Chief.
I really don't deserve such high praise.
You deserve it.
Not only do you deserve it,
but I also want to thank you.
As for a soldier like Guo Zijian,
you didn't lead him astray,
nor did you misguide him.
In the past, a decapitation strike on Long Yuanshan...
he definitely wouldn't have missed it.
But look at him now.
The change is quite obvious.
What does this show?
It's because you
gave your soldiers enough sense of security
and the space to showcase their talents.
You
are a good leader.
Hearing you say this,
I feel quite ashamed.
Actually, I know very well
that there are some things
I haven't done well enough.
Lao Suo.
Let me remind you,
you need to leave room for your own improvement.
A person can't always dwell on past regrets.
You have to realize that it's because of past regrets
that the future can be closer to perfection.
Do you understand what I mean?
Yes, Chief.
Capturing Long Yuanshan this time,
I wasn't as excited as I thought I'd be.
Instead, I felt a kind of
emptiness from losing my goal.
Why do you say that?
I feel that
the help I can provide for Yufeng Battalion
and for Guo Zijian and the others
is becoming less and less.
You're wrong.
Without you,
Yufeng Battalion and Guo Zijian wouldn't be where they are today.
True.
But what about their tomorrow?
Lao Suo.
In the tide of this military reform, we are all just
a single drop of water.
I understand how you feel.
And I know what you're trying to express.
But,
I don't know how to answer you.
Let me offer a phrase for us both to remember.
Look ahead.
Yes, Chief.
If we do the review based on your plan,
I think it's too complicated and unnecessary.
How is it complicated?
A review plan should be
a bit more detailed.
Look here.
Staff Officer Liang is here too.
Battalion Commander Jiang.
What are you here for?
Business.
Battalion Commander, I'll be going then.
No, no, no, Staff Officer Liang.
Hold on.
Come with me.
I've already found a place.
But I still have to be on duty.
Isn't Lao Sang around?
Let's go, let's go.
I'll take you to Deputy Brigade Commander Suo to ask for leave.
Let's go.
You treating me to a meal out of nowhere...
this isn't a setup, is it?
Guo Zijian,
nothing happens for no reason.
Ever since you joined the 396th Brigade,
we haven't seen eye to eye.
Right?
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo suggested
that I have a chat with you.
To clear the air,
so we can work better together moving forward.
This meal was his idea, too.
So, are we talking?
Talk about what? Let's eat first.
Come on, dig in.
Hold on.
Reporting.
Come in.
Guo Zijian,
to tell you the truth,
ever since I met you,
I've never respected you.
It's written all over your face.
I could tell.
Can I continue?
Back then, because of you,
I lost the chance to be a top cadet.
I still don't understand.
I really don't.
Why you would do something
that hurts others without benefiting yourself.
If I didn't fight seriously,
and handed this
promotion spot to you on a silver platter,
would you be proud to be the top cadet?
Your 'fighting seriously'
was turning my staff officer against me,
and having him
respectfully lead you
into my command post
to take me out.
Right?
Thanks a lot.
Speaking of which,
how did you turn him?
Now you're asking me?
That staff officer of yours,
that kid
had his eye on your spot for a while.
You were sold out like a fool,
and you didn't even know it.
You even treated him as a confidant.
A commander like you
in a TV show
would survive one episode at most.
I made you see clearly
this person's true colors.
Don't be ungrateful when you benefited.
What?
I'm supposed to thank you?
No need to be so polite.
Can I continue?
Sure.
Go on.
Air all your grievances.
Then later,
because you forged military orders,
you had me, the 1st Battalion,
and the whole 396th Brigade running in circles.
Tell me yourself,
wasn't that shameless?
It was quite shameless.
The rest of the charges,
I'll list for you.
Being greedy for credit and reckless,
disobeying orders,
and acting willfully,
leading to a crushing defeat against the 404th Brigade.
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo was captured,
and Wu Dongsheng lost his leg.
Still unrepentant,
causing a scene at the Party Committee.
And also,
towards you, my old rival,
I never showed any mercy.
What do you mean, no mercy?
Do I need your mercy?
Spicy chicken,
sliced beef in chili sauce,
twice-cooked pork,
and Mapo tofu.
All extra numbing and spicy,
just your favorites.
I made them all myself.
Great.
Time for a feast.
Too bad we can't drink.
The usual,
tea instead of liquor.
You got it.
What do you mean?
A taste of home.
Stop making a fuss.
Have a seat.
Actually, I've had this thought for a while.
It's just that I've never...
...been able to make up my mind.
Why?
Yufeng Battalion is on the rise right now.
In this recent drill,
we received unanimous praise from our superiors again.
You played a huge part in it.
You have such a bright future ahead of you.
Why leave the army now?
What are you thinking?
What is a soldier's future?
It's dedication.
It's sacrifice.
I told you that when you were a recruit.
Don't you remember?
I remember.
But...
But after all these years,
how much of that have we actually achieved?
You have a deep understanding of everything else.
Except for the very last point.
Guo Zijian, do you know...
...what I can't stand the most about you?
That I'm more handsome than you?
That's not the point.
You have a higher degree than me.
You have more tricks up your sleeve.
You're smarter than me,
and you're more shameless.
You always have the upper hand.
I refused to accept it.
But I couldn't admit defeat.
The entire 2nd Battalion is watching me.
I'm the commander of the 2nd Battalion.
I have to lead the entire 2nd Battalion...
...to keep charging forward.
But I could never catch up to you.
I tried everything, but I just couldn't.
Every time I felt that...
...your little schemes...
...wouldn't be a problem this time...
...and that I could handle them,
you'd always come up with something new.
I was so frustrated.
Why couldn't I catch up?
Why couldn't I catch up to you, Guo Zijian?
Until...
...you dragged me along to see Deputy Brigade Commander Suo.
I finally found the reason.
To be honest,
field training...
...and the application of new equipment...
...do you think I didn't want that?
I did.
But I didn't dare.
I didn't dare to propose it.
But you're different.
You dare to take big strides forward.
You dared to boldly approach Deputy Brigade Commander Suo...
...to state your requests...
...and present your suggestions.
I concede.
As the saying goes,
"A weak soldier fails alone; a weak commander ruins the unit."
As the commander of the 2nd Battalion,
I lack that kind of backbone,
causing all the officers and men of the 2nd Battalion
to stagnate right alongside me.
Even the new sights issued from above,
we didn't dare to use them.
We're not like your 1st Battalion.
Last time,
watching Tan Ke
and Yang Maolin spar,
we lost.
But I wasn't focused on winning or losing.
What I saw was the cohesion of the 1st Battalion.
I saw the soul of the 1st Battalion.
You brought all of that.
That's what our 2nd Battalion lacks.
Thinking back to the past,
in every exercise,
the 1st Battalion was crushed under my feet.
But after you arrived,
going from catching up,
to tying with us,
and then surpassing our 2nd Battalion,
it's all because of you.
Because of a commander like you.
For the sake of combat capability,
you'll do whatever it takes.
No matter how capable I seem,
I still went to
the training unit as an instructor,
served as the support team captain,
and even delivered boxed lunches to you.
Jiang Shengqiang,
I'm not as unfazed as you say.
Ever since
I came to the 396th Brigade,
and went through so much,
deep down,
I've felt bad,
suffered,
and struggled too.
I've even had thoughts of giving up.
But we are soldiers.
We can endure anything,
but we just can't admit defeat.
We can't admit defeat to our opponents,
and we can't admit defeat to ourselves.
That's right.
Can't admit defeat.
The entire process of this exercise,
I observed it all.
To be honest,
if it were our Jufeng Battalion,
wanting to win
would be very difficult.
I admit,
Jufeng Battalion currently falls behind Yufeng Battalion.
But Guo Zijian,
just like you said,
"never admit defeat."
I will never admit defeat.
Our 2nd Battalion won't admit defeat either.
I will keep chasing you,
and always be your rival.
Be careful.
Don't let me surpass you.
I will keep challenging you.
We have a long road ahead.
I'll be waiting.
I look forward to the day you can defeat me.
We'll
let the battlefield decide the hero.
The battlefield
will decide the hero.
Let me ask you something.
You wrote the report letter against Guo Zijian, right?
No need to deny it.
I've read the letter.
From beginning to end,
it was full of your strong personal bias.
Every single thing
was an exaggeration,
blowing things out of proportion.
Right?
I know that
ever since Guo Zijian
messed up our exercise with the Infantry Academy,
you've been holding a grudge
and opposing him at every turn.
Am I right?
I exaggerated?
Isn't he just putting on an act?
As soon as he arrives,
he's right about everything,
and he knows everything.
He always has to show off
his personal brilliance.
He's just an instructor from a military academy.
Could he possibly know better
than those of us on the frontline
who have worked at the grassroots for years?
Does he really understand more?
He says I'm not fit to be the Chief of Training.
Is his way the only right way?
Such expensive equipment,
before a battle is even fought,
just during an exercise,
he practically tried to ruin it.
And
Wu Dongsheng,
such a good soldier,
if it weren't for Guo Zijian's reckless mindset,
would he have lost that leg?
No matter how talented he is,
if everyone in our unit were like him,
it wouldn't take long
before not just his Yufeng Battalion,
but our entire brigade,
would be completely ruined by him, men and gear alike.
He has his problems,
and you have yours.
Me?
Speaking of problems,
Chief,
my big brother,
I have a bellyful of grievances myself.
Fine then,
let's get it all out in the open today.
Pour out all the grievances you have inside.
My grievances
aren't just for myself,
but also for you,
and Lao Jiang.
Go ahead.
I'm listening.
Before Guo Zijian came along,
what was our brigade like?
Weren't we doing just fine?
So why is it that the moment he arrives,
suddenly everything is wrong?
My position as Chief of Operations and Training is gone.
Is Old Jiang really that inferior to him?
His main attack battalion spot is gone too.
And then there's you.
Just how much longer do you plan on sitting
in the Deputy Brigade Commander's seat?
So you wrote the report letter.
Right?